Guide to the Annie Burr Jennings Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Annie Burr Jennings collection
1775-1930
MS 687
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
An autograph collection of approximately forty letters and documents, chiefly dating from the Revolutionary War era. Prominent in the collection are Ashbel Green, James Wadsworth, and George Washington. Among the later writers are Albert Bierstadt, Richard Wagner and correspondents of Annie Burr Jennings.
Jennings, Annie Burr, 1855-1939
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. W. S. Lewis, 1940.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
In 1940 Mrs. Wilmarth S. Lewis gave to Yale University in memory of her aunt, Annie Burr Jennings, a collection of letters and other papers dealing with Aaron Burr and members of his family and related families. These papers were subsequently divided into the Burr Family papers (Manuscript Group Number 303) and the Reeve Family papers (Manuscript Group Number 686). The Annie Burr Jennings Collection is composed of materials which do not pertain directly to either of the other two collections.
Contained here are approximately forty autograph letters and documents, dating for the most part from the Revolutionary War era, and three letters written to Annie Burr Jennings by friends. Among the items of historical interest are a letter of Richard Wagner, one from Samuel Adams to William and Thomas Bradford, a letter from George Washington to his nephew Bushrod Washington, and a letter to George Washington from the architect William Thornton discussing some houses being built by Washington and plans for the capitol.
United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; Autographs; Marie-Amélie, Queen, consort of Louis-Philippe, King of the French, 1782-1866; Adams, Samuel, 1722-1803; Bierstadt, Albert, 1830-1902; Blennerhassett, Harman, 1764-1831; Call, Daniel, approximately 1765-1840; Colden, Cadwallader D. (Cadwallader David), 1769-1834; Green, Ashbel, 1762-1848; Green, E. K.; Green, Jacob, 1722-1790; Jennings, Annie Burr, 1855-1939; Martin, Luther, 1748-1826; Orleans, Antonio d'; Orleans, J. C. d'; Sands, Comfort, 1748-1834; Silliman, Gold Selleck, 1777-1868; Thornton, William, 1759-1828; Wadsworth, James, 1730-1817; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883; Washington, George, 1732-1799; Wickham, John, 1763-1839
- Inventory
  - Correspondence
    - Adams, Samuel to William and Thomas Bradford, 1775 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bierstadt, Albert to unidentified [autograph fragment], undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Blennerhassett, Herman to David Wallace, 1805 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Call, Daniel to Overton Corley, 1805 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Colden, Cadwallader [David] to unidentified, 1795 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Committee of Correspondence of Mechanics and Manufacturers of Providence to mechanics and manufacturers of New London, 1789 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Green, Ashbel to unidentified, 1803 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Green, E. K. to Ashbel Green, 1794, 1801-1802, 1804, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - [Green, Jacob] to Ashbel Green, 1785 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Marie Amélie [queen consort of Louis Phillippe] to Leon Laya, 1853, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Martin, Luther to unidentified, 1795 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - d'Orleans, Antonio to Leon Laya, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - d'Orleans, J. C. to Leon Laya, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Sands, Comfort, to the militia companies of Connecticut, 1775 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Silliman, Gold Selleck, David Wooster, James Wadsworth, and Dyer Throop to the militia companies of Connecticut, 1777 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Thornton, William to George Washington, 1798 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Wadsworth, James to militia companies of Durham, officers, 1779 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Wagner, Richard, to unidentified, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Ward, Andrew, to James WadsworthSee: James Wadsworth, folder 17
  - Washington, George, to Bushrod Washington, 1796 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Wickham, John, to Samuel Greenhow and James Kennedy, 1802-1808 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Special files
    - Poquannock, Connecticut: petition of inhabitants for independent status [photocopy], 1690 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Unidentified militia company muster roll, 1781 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Goodsell, Serviss: commission as captain of 8th company and trainband in the 4th regiment of the State of Connecticut [photocopy], 1782 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Jumel, Stephen: certificate of inspection of goods for export from New York to Bordeaux, 1803 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Annie Burr Jennings correspondence
    - Bryan, Charles S., to A. B. J., 1826 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Sheldon, Louisa Walker (Gulliver), to A. B. J., [1930] (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Shelton, Ada Stewart, to A. B. J., [1929] (Box 1, Folder 27)